okay everyone today is a meeting for on
boarding like on second phase of Journal
transcriptions
project uh first one was last year with
a first uh approach of transcribing and
Publishing of V videos what we have at
the end of this year we also focused
three projects uh for Physics course for
social sciences course and
Symposium to
be transcribed edited and publish
published in text
format so we prepared
some
um some informational team some
informational Niche for team's
work as we used it last year and now
developed ebit
and currently we at the stage that we
have
initial automatic
transcriptions of these
three
materials and uh we need to make
editorial work uh to uh improve
readability uh for
text uh
possibly uh argumented someway uh as uh
Dave's example possibly will share here
too and uh this document was shared for
all
people uh who expressed very interested
to
participate and
now uh before I
start uh describing the structure of
document and work possibly some
questions or related to access or
something to code the document itself
and possibly GitHub
platform okay if not for now let's go
into the
documents so for now uh each uh each
course Physics course social sciences
course and Symposium have separate
documents this uh like different
teams
uh most number of people are in Physics
course so let's go through this
document uh the aim of this document is
like to focus team's attention on to
important steps and for now in simplest
way uh and like a main page to to the
document is to
do uh table which show us work
breakdown what we have in terms of
uh uh video artifacts as lectures and
discussions and now they we have
um uh transcribed and uploaded in into
the
GitHub and uh for so the main goal here
is uh to for people to
choose specific lectures what we're
willing to
work and we will add everyone into the
teams as
editors and for each such editorial work
you have that structure for now it's
presented in in a basic way form but
kind of
straightforward if you don't have issues
with
the uh GitHub
access and uh check right as
an
editor uh you can start work on
it uh watching specific video and
following in the text
here uh and making edits in the text and
then making comments and it will go in
the our for now it will go to the our
main
branch uh without
complicating uh in terms of have
separate separate branch and so
on
uh so for now we can check uh for
Physics
course with people who are now in the
meeting with
us maybe just to give one more kind of
comment or angle there Alex
so um there's a lot of ways to make
these transcripts and the reason why
we've chosen to use GitHub first off so
that everything is open source and all
the commits are traceable and that
because it's a plain text format no one
you know writes their essays with the
start and end times but this plain text
format allows us to dip in later fix a
small typo anyone can look at the open
source version submit a
small change and also this helps a lot
with the different kinds of captioning
translation language modeling ET Etc so
the big picture is like the Koda is for
having Clarity
around who's in what role for the
project and then it will pretty much if
it's being useful just link you to the
GitHub page where you're going to be
actually making the edits you
can clone the repo and make the edits
locally and then push the repos like
with GitHub desktop or you on the top
right can use the pencil icon and do
edits directly in the browser if you do
that um you know don't close the window
before committing your changes make sure
to submit it as Maria nods and
understands um and then we can look or
Alex maybe it'd be useful to just share
how you actually go about doing the
editing but then pretty much do a side
by side with the video and and the
transcript play a few seconds of the
video or keep it playing and then where
you see there to be uh we we'll go
through kind of what does the first
draft
editing entail first just looking to
make what was said accurate like a
Verbatim transcript and then if you have
a extra desire to improve it then
there's things that can happen like
adding in links and images and screen
shots but on a first pass the goal is
just to get the verbatim transcript
accurate um I have a question Alex B
yeah uh so I'm in the page that you're
in in
GitHub and when I click on the little
pencil on the right hand corner I get a
message that says you need to Fork this
repository to propose
changes oh uh please send me
your nickname in GitHub so we will
provide to you access yeah I I I did
send it I sent it this morning so um oh
it's okay
uh I see it that's fine all at it now
Alex just um or just anyone who anyone
who doesn't have GitHub access right now
you only need this one time but if you
don't have that just put your GitHub
user name into the chat on the right and
I'll give it right now
okay sorry about that thank
you okay thank you thank you we'll do
this
yeah let let's get back uh to this
document yeah please if you're in the
document of Physics course and uh going
into work quiz please uh add yourself
here uh this editor role and teams
enroll table just to check that
everything works fine and you're
in and uh
uh our page here data files and links in
the document it shows us for whole list
of transcriptions and going into
the cycle of editing let's just
go
you can open it just from the
table and then press this writing
button make
some I just in the
text and uh after you finished some part
of
working uh this a file just commit
changes commit directly to the main
branch possibly if you feel some
importance of that information about
what changes make some extended
descriptions maybe something totally not
understandable
or some something else what needed
additional attention
so and after that it's saved and we can
see and Trace history of Ed
changes maybe it's could be useful for
you also to see
afterwards some specifics about
it
um some questions for
now uh the only question I have is um
I'm ready to start working on the
project I'm just curious um if
about uh your target date for completion
um for such projects it always was uh
all participants was working with their
own on their own pace uh for sure we
have it uh
usually
silent deadline at the end of the
year but uh we will see how it will go
in terms
of participations and changes and edits
what we'll see next
weeks yeah and also to get it completed
by the end of the year we we don't that
like we'll pick a deadline when whatever
the plain text format is we're just
going to wrap and publish
that um so we'll communicate that but
within the next one or two weeks would
be great for the
edits
[Music]
um and there's kind of the lecture scale
work which is the editing so listening
to it side by side and having the
accurate text um then the kind of
lecture scale plus which is adding the
links and the images and the
enrichment there's there's a a lot that
that can go but we just want a first
minimal relatively verbatim
publication um and in future versioning
we can we can enrich it further and then
there's a little bit of sort of um
course level work like AAL will work on
that for social sciences anyone who
wants to on physics and that'll be like
getting everyone's
Orchid and just preparing the template
making sure the plain text rendering is
looking
good and then
will have a kind of um continuous
deployment and
versioning of of the process and of the
actual
artifacts
okay yeah so the first first task is to
do
the first round of edits for the
existing
transcript and we want to do that you
know as fast as we can I I understand
that that seems reasonable and then
here yeah and the text is is it's more
accurate than
not yeah I noticed
that
so Alex should we allocate the lectures
and just see what we can um what people
want to claim in the
course here and then send out what we
need done further or
what yeah I believe for now it will be
better to add
everyone for the meeting to his team
table
check what everyone is on board here in
the team and when put owners for
specific lectures
and after that person can
see
uh make statuses uh and possibly put
some dates
if you see it
possible
so uh Colin
and you're you're here as
a is this your
email that's not me
oh
I'm not sure
about did you want to do physics Colin
or the social sciences social sciences
following that one okay
yeah oh yes
yeah yeah the same thing is for social
sciences in uh data files and links
all links into GitHub for editing files
is
added uh and for other people
in physics who is not actually here
right now in the
list okay if everyone mostly added
here we can go possibly through the
lecture
list and assign specific
lectures to someone or you can choose
guys right in the
document
just again like on a kind of pragmatic
note it depends a lot on the
speakers um how well they were picked up
by the
transcription at the word level and
sentence level
Etc um somewhere between like 1 and a
half and
twox of the amount of time of the
lecture if you're half the time you're
you're playing and half the time you're
not
then a 1- hour lecture will take two
hours to
review it's a great learning experience
like you really do slow down and
contemplate the ideas and of course the
outcome leverages a lot of other
people's learning
too um but any any uncertainties or
notes that you have about doing the
editing also feel free to to know in the
Koda or or pass
on as this is kind of a keystone
practice for improving the
texts an advanced speech to text helps
get the first draft
further and then people can like look
under the life life cycle
section where there's further
definitions of the working products and
and the tools and all of
this and so that that is kind of like a
meta SL important way of working
with the artifact based role
assignments and just making sure we have
it all
clear yeah yeah thank you and also the
sections in the document of change and
suggestions you always can put something
that we can afterwards uh work with and
update our templates our projects uh Pro
to put improvements for evolving
ofare uh so as I see uh we have uh that
teams
is like full and completed for
now so next step just
put yourself
some
lecture and then follow this task and uh
again the basic instructions
here all our questions through the work
in terms of if you have some technical
issues
or terms of access or
something just contact by email or in
Discord and we will address
it
Dave is there anything you
wna bring up like just about the
transcription codes or about any other
things that might be
helpful yeah it might be uh helpful to
look at um the work that I've done on
lecture one just step through that uh so
anything that I'm not doing well people
can point that out or anything that's
not clear how I'm accomplishing a
particular item they can uh ask or I can
yeah now I'm sharing it how it looks
like and it's kind of argum argumented
with the
graphics Y and uh possibly some people
can see it as example of
formating that we can use as example and
reference how to work with
it yeah I brought in the the new
transcription codes just in case um
people want to see but basically the um
square brackets followed by rounded
brackets is the standard link notation
and if you put an exclamation point
before the square bracket that's where
you get an image so again don't worry
about the images or
link if you if you don't want to but
this is an examp Le of
um what it renders out
to when it's when it's written out that
way also this has Bolding of the first
time that a technical term or entity is
used which is standard textbook practice
and in the square brackets single square
brackets is standard editorial
commentary so like church and turn in
Alonzo church and Alan
Turing so again first focus is just
verbatim no need for um or
uh or anything like that just kind of
um lightly
clarified straight
verbatim um if there's like something
that that you're not sure about like if
it's a factual
inaccuracy um
or somebody starts one sentence and then
goes to a different
sentence again just note them but on the
first pass just focus on what should be
shown in the
subtitles with a light editorial
touch and then this is cross rendered to
the subtitles and the
translations and so
on and also again this format rests in
the
GitHub so we continue to improve the the
quality the
underlying resource and then also over
in the in the kind of cousin
repo utilities that's where we develop
the the tools to
render make websites and um
outputs static outputs and custom
websites
from the the plain Tex format that is in
the journal
repo and Dave something
else um well that's a good youw um do
you I I believe everything that I've
used we've either talked about it
several times in chats or it's
off-the-shelf Universal markdown codes
like the link and
um uh image now the one thing that that
um might might take a look at again is
in that transcript for lecture
one um look couple of things in there if
you can bring that up
Alex the
code yeah good um in the yeah in code uh
the first line now I thought I had fixed
that to be a title but I'm not quite
clear if if there's something wrong with
that that it that that there's that you
can't use title in like in line one does
it look like it put um an explanation in
there which makes it unresolved because
it's not well formed markdown it was
supposed to be just
um yeah what my in the square bracket is
not closed I think either correct remove
the exclamation point in the first
bracket and then it should render as
H1 yeah do you want to check that Alex
just d drop those first two characters
from line one and then go back to
preview and then we can St I can stop
worrying about that yeah just the first
two characters on the first
line this one yeah okay and Now preview
and then commit changes oh right thank
you yeah actually you don't even need to
preview okay good that's what I was
looking for thank you okay and the other
thing coming back
um okay come back to code um there was a
very minor factual error that you can
see down here pretty close to the well
look for solve asol
VY which stram search do a search uh uh
control
F okay this is not standard this is not
document any place we've talked about it
but I just want to you know because you
can't go out and look at markdown
information and see what's going on
it'll be and search for what sorry
s VA a
y okay good good good yeah there we go
uh Chris had a just a minor um uh
factual error in here he clearly
referring to the fifth solv Conference
of 1927 he said first solve Conference
of 1928 so I just took those two words
fifth I inserted Fifth and marked first
for
deletion same thing insert 1927 delete
1928 so if you see something that you
don't want to falsify what the speaker
has said you preserve that by having by
enclosing it in um the curly
braces but you want to do an insertion
so that everyone that looks at that will
know what the facts are people won't go
crazy trying to figure out what is this
first the first SV conferences in 1899
or whatever the deal was uh if that
seems objectionable and I was doing more
more editing
than many people are going to be called
on many people all you want to do is get
the words on the paper the same as what
came out of the speaker's mouth so you
won't go to this level you're not going
to do fact checking except as Daniel
said maybe make a note you know next
person who edits this go check that do a
fact check on that or listen more
carefully or ask somebody else what did
this guy say is this all does this make
sense that makes a lot of sense to me um
I think my main question
is um
GitHub and is new to me and who can I
contact or who should I
contact at your
Institute with problems that I may be
having technical problems with
GitHub I think one great spot thank you
would be the journal Discord
Channel like just posting
there or um Alex Dave Polly or I okay as
kind of being that that's good or just
in the the project and then at the end
all of the kind of threads of questions
we'll fold it back into our
documentation and
onboarding so you know hit every speed
bump you can and then we'll learn all
these different um ways
to make it
easier got it
okay
good okay some our
questions let's just have anyone who
wants to yeah choose a lecture or
discussion and then um by the by the by
tomorrow
whatever isn't already
claimed we can send out to those who
aren't
here and then yeah um on the on the
journal side
let's coordinate around what other
information do we need like are we going
to try to get the orci ID for every
single speaker or is there any other
kind of course level information that we
need to prepare for the publication test
out the publishing um rendering
Pipeline and then if we uh and then um
we'll set the the um
editorial it's not a freeze deadline
because of course people can continue to
edit GA but we'll pick the deadline that
we plan to wrap the
version and then um we pretty much
compile and compose each of these
products upload them onto zenodo get the
DOI make a version in GitHub of a
release and then continue going from
there um yeah uh hly possibly you can
share some updates on site of compiling
after we'll have edits and place so for
now as I understand it's will be
mostly automated
approach uh what we can like possibly
test or on some bench of edits or
something yes I can um I think I'm going
to start working with uh Dave's uh
transcript where he has some of these
other additional uh ways of marking up
uh the transcript and so then we want to
be able to support those as people add
them uh like the uh curly braces for
example first versus fifth uh so if we
can if I can start to automate that and
eventually create um an SRT file and a
markdown file and that markdown file can
then also be converted to a PDF um for a
final uh
publication so that's kind of what I'm
working on is the is the last step
also to the translation point on
Magdalena that you had raised from
the um
snapshot accurate English
translation then we
could we could Branch into a translation
from there and and also explore that
potentially keeping it within the same
plain text format maybe using language
model um and then and then figure out
again these these next questions like
how do we keep um multiple translations
versioned within the same repo but have
them all lined up in the same captioning
and rendering
pipeline um yeah so with with a
translation I imagine that
we there has to be consensus about the
final product in English
right and then the translation can
start yeah yeah for for this one we'll
focus on the the trunk of getting the
English versioning accurate and then and
then transpose it um but you know in the
coming years in journal we'll explore
every combination of starting language
and target language and everything
yes that would be
great okay
so I'll take lecture three I can't add
my name yet because of my access issue
but
do
okay I reinvites your ASU
email to physics so so you should have
that but I but um I'll I'll add you to
three
okay
uh okay if no other questions for now
possibly we can stop the
recording any last questions or I'll
stop it
now looks
like